Guide to the Richard and Mildred Crooks Collection
Stanford Archive of Recorded Sound
Richard and Mildred Crooks Collection
1913-1984
ARS-0004
Richard and Mildred Crooks
9 linear ft.
Stanford Archive of Recorded Sound Stanford University Libraries Stanford, California 94305-3076
Materials documenting virtually every stage of Crooks career.
Access
Collection is open for research. Listening appointments may require 24 hours notice. Contact the Archive Operations Manager.
Biography / Administrative History
Alexander Richard Crooks, tenor, was born in Trenton, N.J. on June 26, 1900. He toured widely, and sang with the Metropolitan Opera Company from 1933 to 1942. Crooks recorded extensively for the Victor record company, and was featured on several radio series from 1929 to 1945. He married his childhood friend Mildred Pine in 1921 and they had two children, Patricia and Richard, Jr. In retirement, the couple settled in Portola Valley. Richard Crooks died on September 30, 1972.
Scope and Content of Collection
Materials documenting virtually every stage of Crooks' career, starting with newspaper clippings and programs apparently kept by his mother from his appearances as a boy soprano in churches, at resort concerts and in vaudeville. Included are materials related to Crooks' high school classmate George Antheil. The collection contains photographs, programs, and other items for nearly every role Crooks undertook at the Metropolitan Opera and memorabilia from the numerous concert tours and the years broadcasting the Voice of Firestone radio program (1932-1945), as well as sheet music. Included are letters from colleagues and friends from throughout his career and into retirement. Finally, Crooks' own recording collection, with test pressings, privately recorded materials, and several air checks (with Bing Crosby) are included.
Arrangement
Organized into 12 series. I. Correspondence. II. Documents. III. Programs. IV. Photographs. V. Scrapbooks. VI. Clippings. VII. Publications. VIII. Libretti. IX. Sheet music. X. Sound recordings. XI. Audio-visual materials. XII. Miscellany.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Crooks, Richard, 1900-1972.; Voice of Firestone (Radio program); Tenors (Singers); Opera.
Container List
- Correspondence
  - Correspondence-Durant (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence-Melchior (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence-RCA (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence-Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence 1913-1939 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence 1940-1948 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence 1953-1959 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence 1960-1971 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence 1972 (Condolences) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence 1980-1984 (Mildred Crooks) (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Documents
  - Documents -- Award certificates (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Documents -- Honorary Doctorates (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Documents -- Interviews and Articles 1937-1985 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Documents -- Publicity and Press Releases (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Documents -- Radio transcripts, 1948, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Documents -- Closing night at the old Met, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Documents -- Mildred Crooks and George Antheil poems (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Documents -- Biography (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Documents -- Mildred's various notes (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Documents -- Lists. Selections from the recordings of Richard Crooks (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Programs
  - Programs -- Opera snakes, 1912, 1933, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Programs -- Firestone programs list (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Programs -- Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Programs -- 1913-1931 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Programs -- 1936 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Programs -- 1939-1940 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Programs -- 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Programs -- 1943-1952 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Programs -- non-Crooks (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Photographs
  - Photographs -- Portraits (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Photographs -- Richard and Mildred Crooks (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Photographs -- at Buck Hill Falls with family (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Photographs -- Recreation--New Jersey, 1935 and earlier (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Photographs -- Recreation--General (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Photographs -- Victor Male Chorus, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Photographs -- Hamburg and Berlin debuts, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Photographs -- Canada and Sweden concerts (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Photographs -- World Tour, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Photographs -- Seattle, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Photographs -- World Tour, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Photographs -- Metropolitan Opera (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Photographs -- Metropolitan Opera -- Faust (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Photographs -- Metropolitan Opera -- Linda di Chamounix (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Photographs -- Metropolitan Opera -- Manon (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Photographs -- Metropolitan Opera -- Mignon (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Photographs -- Metropolitan Opera -- Traviata (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Photographs -- Firestone Broadcast (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Photographs -- Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Photographs -- with others (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Photographs -- Others I (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Photographs -- Others II (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Scrapbooks
  - Fragments of scrapbook 1914-1919, 15" x 12 1/4'' gray cloth cover (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Dated Feb. 25, 1933, 14.5" x 12'' black leather covers with loose pages (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - World Tour, 1936, 14" x 9 3/4'' beige, green, brown and yellow cloth covers, with leather strap for gathering pages. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Publicity book for the Melbourne season of Richard Crooks, 1936. Vol.3, 13" x 8 1/2''gray paper covers (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Publicity book for the Melbourne season of Richard Crooks, 1936. Vol.3, 14 1/2" x 9 1/2''gray cloth covers (Box 7, Folder 5)
    Bound copies of scrapbook 4
- Clippings
  - (Oversize 8)
- Publications
  - The Metropolitan Opera Fête. February 26, 1977. Boston Opera Association (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - The Life of Emma Thursby. 1845-1931 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    Inscribed by Ina Love Thursby. Feb. 21, 1941
  - Flagstad. A personal memoir (Box 9, Folder 3)
    Inscribed by ?. Feb. 9, 1983
- Libretti
  - Donizetti, Gaetano, 1797-1848. Linda di Chamounix (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Donizetti, Gaetano, 1797-1848. Don Pasquale (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Sullivan, Arthur, Sir, 1842-1900. H.M.S. Pinafore (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912. Manon (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Thomas, Ambroise, 1811-1896. Mignon (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Prokofiev, Sergey, 1891-1953. Love for three oranges (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Puccini, Giacomo, 1858-1924. Turandot (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Rodgers, Richard, 1902- Carousel (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Macbeth (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Rigoletto (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Otello (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Traviata (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Sheet music
  - Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Lieder, op. 49. Wiegenlied (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Carissimi, Giacomo, 1605-1674. Vittoria, mio core (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Chenoweth, Wilbur, 1899-1980. Vocalise (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Confrey, Zez, 1895-1971. Kitten on the keys (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Donizetti, Gaetano, 1797-1848. Elisir d'amore (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Firestone, Idabelle. If I could tell you (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Firestone, Idabelle. In my garden (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Gabrilowitsch, Ossip, 1878-1936. Good-bye (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Gluck, Christoph Willibald, Ritter von, 1714-1787. Paride ed Elena. O del mio dolce ardor (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Godard, Benjamin, 1849-1895. Jocelyn. Berceuse (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759. Floridante. Alma mia, Manuscript (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759. Atlanta. Dii ad Irene (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759. Partenope. Sei mia gioia (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759. Judas Maccabaeus. Sound an alarm (copy 1) (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759. Judas Maccabaeus. Sound an alarm (copy 2) (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759. Judas Maccabaeus. Sound an alarm, Manuscript (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759. Samson. Total eclipse; Alexander Balus. To God, who made the radiant sun (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759. Semele. Where'er you walk (copy 1) (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759. Semele. Where'er you walk (copy 2) (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759. Acis and Galatea. Would you gain the tender creature (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Hupfeld, Herman, 1894-1951. Casablanca. As time goes by (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Kern, Jerome, 1885-1945. Very warm for May. All the things you are (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Kodaly, Zolt#225;n, 1882-1967. Psalmus Hungaricus (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - La Forge, Frank, 1879-1953. Schlupfwinkel (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Liszt, Franz, 1811-1886. Oh! quand je dors (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912. Elegy (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Rimsky-Korsakov, Nikolay, 1844-1908. Romansy, op. 2. Vostochnyi romans (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Pessard, Emile, 1843-1917. Adieu du matin (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Respighi, Ottorino, 1879-1936. Stornellatrice (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Du bist die Ruh (copy 1) (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Du bist die Ruh (copy 2) (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Allmacht (chorus) (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Lieder, op. 48. Freundliche Vision (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Lieder, op. 27. Morgen (copy 1) (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Lieder, op. 27. Morgen (copy 2), Manuscript insert with cello obligato (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Lieder, op. 10. Nacht (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Lieder, op. 10. Zueignung (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Strickland, Lily, 1887-1958. Mah Lindy Lou. (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Trunk, Richard. Schlichte Weisen. Mir träumte von einem Königskind (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893. Pesni dlia detei. Legenda (chorus) (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Wesendonck-Lieder. Träume (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Warren, Elinor Remick, 1900- For you with love (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Warren, Elinor Remick, 1900- Christmas Candle (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Warren, Elinor Remick, 1900- Sailing Homeward (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - Warren, Elinor Remick, 1900- Through my open window (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - Warren, Elinor Remick, 1900- Time, you old gipsy man (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - Wolf, Hugo, 1860-1903. Mörike-Lieder. Er ist's (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - O'Connor, Donald, 1925- Favorite Songs (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - Cole, Nat King, 1917-1965. Song album of recorded hits (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - Ay-ay-ay: Creole song (Box 10, Folder 50)
- Sound recordings
  - Voice of Firestone, Tape 1A (Box 11, Folder 1)
    Friml, Rudolf, 1879-1972. Firefly. Donkey serenade -- Waltzing Matilda (Song) -- Drink to me only with thine eyes -- Luening, Otto. 1900- Songs (1922). In Weihnachtszeiten. English
  - Voice of Firestone, Tape dub 4A & 4B (Box 11, Folder 1)
    Alb#233;niz, Isaac, 1860-1909. M#233;lodies. Retreat -- Goodbye -- Chevauchée cosaque -- Kramer, A. Walter (Arthur Walter), 1890-1969. Last hour -- May night -- Hageman, Richard, 1882-1966. Do not go, my love -- Dedication
  - Voice of Firestone, Tape 1B (Box 11, Folder 2)
    Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Herz und Mund und Tat und Leben, BWV 147. Jesus bleibet meine Freude -- Thine alone -- Händel, George Frideric, 1685-1759. Serse. Ombra mai f#249
  - Voice of Firestone, Tape dub 1A & 1B (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Friml, Rudolf, 1879-1972. Firefly. Donkey serenade -- Waltzing Matilda (Song) -- Drink to me only with thine eyes -- Luening, Otto. 1900- Songs (1922). In Weihnachtszeiten. English -- Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Herz und Mund und Tat und Leben, BWV 147. Jesus bleibet meine Freude -- Thine alone -- Händel, George Frideric, 1685-1759. Serse. Ombra mai f#249
  - Voice of Firestone, Tape dub 1A & 1B (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Voice of Firestone, Tape 2A (Box 11, Folder 5)
    Come love with me -- Fox, Oscar J., 1879-1961. Hills of home -- My message -- Del Riego, Teresa, 1876-1968. Homing -- Glazunov, Aleksandr Konstantinovich, 1865-1936. Eiukhnem. English
  - Voice of Firestone, Tape 2B (Box 11, Folder 6)
    Glazunov, Aleksandr Konstantinovich, 1865-1936. Eiukhnem. English -- Bellman -- Strickland, Lily, 1887-1958. Mah Lindy Lou -- Kelley, Daniel E., 1843-1905. Home on the range -- Valerius, Adriaan, d. 1625. Neder-Landtsche gedenck-clanck. Hey wilder dan wild. English
  - Voice of Firestone, Tape dub 2A& 2B (Box 11, Folder 7)
    Come love with me -- Fox, Oscar J., 1879-1961. Hills of home -- My message -- Del Riego, Teresa, 1876-1968. Homing -- Glazunov, Aleksandr Konstantinovich, 1865-1936. Eiukhnem. English -- Glazunov, Aleksandr Konstantinovich, 1865-1936. Eiukhnem. English -- Bellman -- Strickland, Lily, 1887-1958. Mah Lindy Lou -- Kelley, Daniel E., 1843-1905. Home on the range -- Valerius, Adriaan, d. 1625. Neder-Landtsche gedenck-clanck. Hey wilder dan wild. English
  - Voice of Firestone, Tape dub 2A& 2B (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Voice of Firestone, Tape 4A (Box 11, Folder 9)
    Alb#233;niz, Isaac, 1860-1909. M#233;lodies. Retreat -- Goodbye -- Chevauchée cosaque -- Kramer, A. Walter (Arthur Walter), 1890-1969. Last hour -- May night.
  - Voice of Firestone, Tape 4B (Box 11, Folder 10)
    Hageman, Richard, 1882-1966. Do not go, my love -- Dedication
  - Voice of Firestone, Tape dub 4A & 4B (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Voice of Firestone, Tape dub 4A & 4B (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Voice of Firestone, Tape 5A (Box 11, Folder 13)
    Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912. Werther. Pourquoi me r#233;veiller -- Sullivan, Arthur Seymour, Sir, 1842-1900. Gondoliers. Take a pair of sparkling eyes
  - Voice of Firestone, Tape 5B (Box 11, Folder 14)
    Olcott, Chauncey, 1858-1932. Romance of Athlone. My wild Irish rose -- Dawn of freedom -- Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893. Romansy, op. 6. Net, tol'ko tot, kto znal -- Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759. Semele. Where'er you walk
  - Voice of Firestone, Tape dub 5A & 5B (Box 11, Folder 15)
    Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912. Werther. Pourquoi me r#233;veiller -- Sullivan, Arthur Seymour, Sir, 1842-1900. Gondoliers. Take a pair of sparkling eyes -- Olcott, Chauncey, 1858-1932. Romance of Athlone. My wild Irish rose -- Dawn of freedom -- Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893. Romansy, op. 6. Net, tol'ko tot, kto znal -- Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759. Semele. Where'er you walk
  - Voice of Firestone, Tape dub 5A & 5B (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Voice of Firestone, Tape 6A (Box 12, Folder 17)
    Stölzel, Gottfried Heinrich, 1690-1749. Bist du bei mir. English -- Going home --Lord's Prayer.
  - Voice of Firestone, Tape 6B (Box 12, Folder 18)
    Rachmaninoff, Sergei, 1873-1943. Romansy, op. 26. K detyam --Trek song -- Warren, Elinor Remick, 1900- Christmas candle
  - Voice of Firestone, Tape dub 6A & 6B (Box 12, Folder 19)
    Stölzel, Gottfried Heinrich, 1690-1749. Bist du bei mir. English -- Going home --Lord's Prayer -- Rachmaninoff, Sergei, 1873-1943. Romansy, op. 26. K detyam --Trek song -- Warren, Elinor Remick, 1900- Christmas candle.
  - Voice of Firestone, Tape dub 6A & 6B (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Voice of Firestone, Tape B (Box 12, Folder 21)
    Side 1. Somewhere a voice is calling -- Neapolitan love song -- Le reve -- Passing by -- Godard, Benjamin, 1849-1895. Jocelyn. Berceuse -- Rubinstein, Anton, 1829-1894. Soir#233;es #224; Saint-P#233;tersbourg. Romance. English -- Songs of songs -- I hear again as in a dream -- Side 2. Fox, Oscar J., 1879-1961. Hills of home -- Franck, C#233;sar, 1822-1890. Panis angelicus. English -- Herbert, Victor, 1859-1924. Only girl. When you're away -- Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907. Lieder, op. 48. Traum. English -- Drink to me only with thine eyes --Stolz, Robert, 1880-1975. Verlorene Walzer. Selections. English -- Rose of Tralee -- Cowles, Eugene, 1860-1948. Forgotten.
  - Voice of Firestone, Tape C (Box 12, Folder 22)
    Side 1. Bradbury, William B. (William Batchelder), 1816-1868. He leadeth me -- Mother MacRee -- Kashmiri love song -- We're 100 pipers -- Gypsy moon -- Twenty-third Psalm -- Firestone closing theme -- Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907. Hjertets melodier. Jeg elsker dig -- Aubade -- Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Allmacht (Chorus) (with Firestone Chorus) Side 2. Donizetti, Gaetano, 1797-1848. Elisir d'amore. Furtiva lagrima. English -- Balfe, M. W. (Michael William), 1808-1870. Bohemian girl. Then you'll remember me -- Foster, Stephen Collins, 1826-1864. Come where my love lies dreaming -- Mason, Lowell, 1792-1872. Nearer my God to Thee -- Firestone, Idabelle. Melody of love -- Herbert, Victor, 1859-1924. Naughty Marietta. Ah! sweet mystery of life -- A little love, a little kiss -- Salute to the Armed Forces -- Rouget de Lisle, Claude Joseph, 1760-1836. Marseillaise -- Take me back to my boots and saddles
  - Voice of Firestone, Treasury song parade (Box 12, Folder 23)
    Fox, Oscar J., 1879-1961. Hills of home -- Gounod, Charles, 1818-1893. Ave Maria (Vocal version) -- Mother of mine -- Westendorf, Thomas P. I'll take you home again, Kathleen -- Herbert, Victor, 1859-1924. Only girl. When you're away -- (Buy bonds intro) -- Elgar, Edward, 1857-1934. Land of hope and glory, voice, piano --
  - Voice of Firestone "Hills of Home", 5'' tape (Box 12, Folder 24)
    (according to insert this is a dub of 2A & 2B, but due to size it can't be complete) Come love with me -- Fox, Oscar J., 1879-1961. Hills of home -- My message -- Del Riego, Teresa, 1876-1968. Homing -- Glazunov, Aleksandr Konstantinovich, 1865-1936. Eiukhnem. English -- Glazunov, Aleksandr Konstantinovich, 1865-1936. Eiukhnem. English -- Bellman -- Strickland, Lily, 1887-1958. Mah Lindy Lou -- Kelley, Daniel E., 1843-1905. Home on the range -- Valerius, Adriaan, d. 1625. Neder-Landtsche gedenck-clanck. Hey wilder dan wild. English
  - Firestone Hour & other sources from Mildred Crooks (Box 12, Folder 25)
    Dubbed from original tapes, duplicates.
  - Gilmour's Album. Radio Canada, 5" tape (Box 12, Folder 26)
    Quality poor, probably recorded off the air. Not much. Crooks songs.
  - Gilmour's Album. Radio CanadaJune 21, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 27)
    Good quality tape. Edited and recorded on cassette no. XII
  - Gilmour's Album. Tribute to Richard Crooks. Radio CanadaJune 24, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 28)
    Good quality tape. Edited and recorded on cassette no. XII. Trans-Canada Network (East) prepared and deliverd by Clyde Gilmour, movie-critic and record columnist for Toronto Telegram. Salute to Mr. Crooks on his 63rd birthday.
  - Golden Voices, Program 8: Richard Crooks, tenor (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Stars of the Metropolitan Opera (Box 12, Folder 30)
    Side 1. Women's voices --Side 2. Crooks
  - Radio program: Birthday salute to Richard Crooks, from The vocal scene, hosted by George Jelinek on WQXRJune 25, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Metropolitan Opera interview with Richard Crooks (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Interview with Richard Crooks by Richard Vincent, music critic of Albany times Union.Jan. 12, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 33)
    Telephone interview with Richard Crooks, the phone connection causing distortion of this voice. Includes several songs.
  - German arias & To the children (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - Piano music performed by Mary Lee Shepard I (Box 13, Folder 35)
    Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Fantasien, piano, op. 116 -- Rachmaninoff, Sergei, 1873-1943. Morceaux de fantaisie, op. 3. El#233;gie -- Chopin, Fr#233;d#233;ric, 1810-1849. Andante spianato et Grande polonaise brillante. Andante spianato
  - Piano music performed by Mary Lee Shepard II (Box 13, Folder 36)
    Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Variations, piano, WoO 80, C minor -- Rachmaninoff, Sergei, 1873-1943. Selections. Preludes, piano, D Major; E-flat Major; and B minor.
  - Opera arias and songs (Box 13, Folder 37)
    Side 1. Romeo and Juliet. Farewell aria -- Puccini, Giacomo, 1858-1924. Tosca. Selection -- Godard, Benjamin, 1849-1895. Jocelyn. Berceuse -- Bizet, Georges, 1838-1875. Carmen. Fleur que tu m'avais jet#233;e. (in German) -- Dawn of freedom -- Rachmaninoff, Sergei, 1873-1943. Romansy, op. 26. K detyam -- Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907. Hjertets melodier. Jeg elsker dig -- Do not go my love -- Chevauchez cosaque -- Sailing homeward -- Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Herz und Mund und Tat und Leben, BWV 147. Jesus bleibet meine Freude Side 2. Songs, some with piano accompaniment.
  - Richard Crooks: 1917 test 62360 (Box 13, Folder 38)
    The Americans come / Wilbur, Foster
  - Songs; Finlandia. Tape D (Box 13, Folder 39)
    Side 1. Romeo and Juliet -- Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907. Hjertets melodier. Jeg elsker dig -- Old English. Drink to me only with thine eyes -- Pearl fishers -- Sleigh -- Lehmann, Liza, 1862-1918. In a Persian garden. Ah, moon of my delight -- Over there -- Dawn of freedom -- Donizetti, Gaetano, 1797-1848. Elisir d'amore. Furtiva lagrima. Side 2. Finlandia
  - Richard Crooks Souvenirs (Box 13, Folder 40)
    Side 1. Hardelot, Guy d', 1858-1936. Because -- Rimsky-Korsakov, Nikolay, 1844-1908. Sadko (Opera). Song of India -- Mother o' mine -- A dream -- Elegie -- Good-bye. Side 2. Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907. Hjertets melodier. Jeg elsker dig -- Godard, Benjamin, 1849-1895. Jocelyn. Berceuse -- Herbert, Victor, 1859-1924. Only girl. When you're away -- Herbert, Victor, 1859-1924. Naughty Marietta. I'm falling in love with someone; Ah! sweet mystery of life -- Sullivan, Arthur Seymour, Sir, 1842-1900. Lost chord.
  - 78 rpm recordings of various opera singers dubbed onto tape by Charles Riddell (Box 13, Folder 41)
    Includes performers Paul Althouse, Lucy Isabelle March, Rosa Ponselle, Giovanni Martinelli, Edmond Clement, Geraldine Ferrar, Enrico Caruso, Mario Chamlee, Lucrezia Bori, Beniamino Gigli, Giuseppe de Luca, Lambert Murphy, Ernestine Schumann-Heink, Wilfred Glenn, Lawrence Tibbett, John Charles Thomas, Harry Macdonough, Richard Bonelli, Rinald Werrenrath and Nelson Eddy.
  - Stainer, John, Sir, 1840-1901. Crucifixion (Box 13, Folder 42)
    Sung by Richard Crooks and Lawrence Tibbett with Trinity Choir, Mark Andrews, organist. Originally recorded May, 1929 (from Victor M-64?)
  - Music from Elaine Griffing's [sp?] wedding (Box 13, Folder 43)
    For you with love / Warren (written for Elaine Griffin's wedding) Wedding march -- Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Herz und Mund und Tat und Leben, BWV 147. Jesus bleibet meine Freude. Performed by Richard Crooks and Warren, (?) organ.
  - Songs (Box 13, Folder 44)
    Somewhere a voice is calling -- Rouget de Lisle, Claude Joseph, 1760-1836. Marseillaise -- Wood, Haydn, 1882-1959. Roses of Picardy -- Gipsy moon -- Over there -- Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Ellens Gesang, D. 839 -- If I could tell you -- Many trials. Side 2 is blank.
  - Unkown (Box 13, Folder 45)
  - Crooks. Christmas 91, 1/4" tape on a 10 1/2" reel with a 3" NAB hub (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - Voice of Firestone (Radio program): Richard Crooks. NBC NetMay 9, 1943, Transcription disc: 33 1/3 rpm, acetate; 10 in. (Box 14, Folder 1)
    Howard Barlow and Orchestra. Parts 1 and 2 of 6
  - Voice of Firestone (Radio program): Richard Crooks. NBC NetMay 9, 1943, Transcription disc: 33 1/3 rpm, acetate; 10 in. (Box 14, Folder 2)
    Howard Barlow and Orchestra. Parts 3 and 4 of 6
  - Voice of Firestone (Radio program): Richard Crooks. NBC NetMay 9, 1943, Transcription disc: 33 1/3 rpm, acetate; 10 in. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    Howard Barlow and Orchestra. Parts 5 and 6 of 6